<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>trumpet on Universal</title>
    <link>http://learningfromthelegends.com/tags/trumpet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in trumpet on Universal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://learningfromthelegends.com/tags/trumpet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Rolf Smedvig Trumpet Exercise Book Now Available!</title>
      <link>http://learningfromthelegends.com/blog/2018/01/11/rolf-smedvig-trumpet-exercise-book-now/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://learningfromthelegends.com/blog/2018/01/11/rolf-smedvig-trumpet-exercise-book-now/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a couple of years since we released the Rolf Smedvig Haydn and Hummel Trumpet Concerto DVDs. One of the things that was mentioned in the DVDs is that some bonus technical exercises were included with the product. Many of you have written in to ask about these as you couldn&amp;rsquo;t find them under the DVD bonus features section.
Before Rolf&amp;rsquo;s tragic passing he had given us a stack of hand-written exercises and notes for us to publish an exercise booklet as a companion to the DVDs, along with the beautiful editions of the concertos that are already available for free download on our website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High Definition Streaming Now Available!</title>
      <link>http://learningfromthelegends.com/blog/2017/03/28/high-definition-streaming-now-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://learningfromthelegends.com/blog/2017/03/28/high-definition-streaming-now-available/</guid>
      <description>Trumpet DVD Testimonials It’s been a year since we released the Haydn and Hummel Trumpet Concerto DVDs from the legendary Rolf Smedvig, and look at some of the great feedback we’ve been receiving:
&amp;quot;These are excellent pedagogical videos... they are Rolf&#39;s parting legacy for young trumpeters and their teachers.&amp;quot; -- Barry Kilpatrick, Reviewer, American Record Guide (January/February 2016 edition)  &amp;quot;Smedvig’s pedagogical advice is excellent… The value of this resource is immense for musicians of all levels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two New Trumpet DVDs Shipping Today!</title>
      <link>http://learningfromthelegends.com/blog/2015/12/01/two-new-trumpet-dvds-shipping-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://learningfromthelegends.com/blog/2015/12/01/two-new-trumpet-dvds-shipping-today/</guid>
      <description>Learning from the Legends made history in 2014 by publishing the first-ever set of classical music education lessons meant for advanced students, and the release was a smashing success! Just look at some of these testimonials we received for our Mendelssohn and Bruch DVDs from luminaries such as John Corigliano, Aaron Dworkin, and Philippe Quint. In that initial post we said that our long term goal was to “expand our line to include all the string, brass, and woodwind instruments as well as several vocal ranges.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>